ZAHIDULHOSSAIN

FRONT END DEVELOPER

CONTACTS

ISTANBUL, TURKEY



+90 - 5530 - 76 - 82 - 78



zhchoyan@gmail.com



www.linkedin.com/in/choyan

EDUCATION

MASTERS IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING

Konya Technical University 2018 - Current

BACHELOR IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING International University of Business Agriculture and Technology 2013 - 2016

PERSONAL INFO

NATIONALITY: BANGLADESHI

MARRITAL STATUS: SINGLE

Dob: 10TH SEPTEMBER 1992

ABOUT ME

I am Innovative, creative, and a team player. I have six years of experience in building, developing, and managing websites, and applications for various companies. I am interested in achieving a position in a challenging environment that focuses on research and development. I am looking for my next role in a diverse and inclusive team where I will be able to challenge myself with distinct workflow and technologies.

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR FRONT-END DEVELOPER

MAKDOS BILISIM | JAN. 2020 - CURRENT | ISTANBUL, TURKEY

- Developing rich user interfaces for their upcoming mail delivery platform.
- Implementing real-time data fetching using WebSocket API to enhance user engagement.
- Supervising and mentoring Junior Developers in different projects to boost up productivity and implement state-of-the-art solutions for complicated problems.

Technology: ReactJS, React Native, Gatsby, NextJS, WebSocket, PWA, Zustand

FRONT-END ENGINEER

KODEEO | OCT. 2018 - DEC. 2019 | DHAKA, BANGLADESH

- I was leading their Front-end team to develop a rich multi-vendor and multi-auth Point of Sale system with Vue.JS.
- Lead the Front-end team for the development of a multi-vendor ecommerce platform with Nuxt.JS. Applied various Nuxt modules for the development of its Authentication system and SEO.

Technology: VueJS, VueX, NuxtJS, PWA

RESEARCH FELLOW

BANGABANDHU SHEIKH MUJIBUR RAHMAN AGRICULTURAL UNIVERSITY | FEB. 2017 - APRIL. 2017 | DHAKA, BANGLADESH

- I was responsible for Developing an android application for the farmers to train them about various crop-related diseases.
- Surveyed and analyzed the result of the usage of the application.
- Engineered in the Deployment of the E-Village data center.

Technology: Ionic framework, Cordova, WordPress

LANGUAGE

BENGALI



ENGLISH



TURKISH



EXPERIENCE

FRONT END DEVELOPER

KODEEO | JAN. 2014 - JULY. 2016 | DHAKA, BANGLADESH

- Writing Pixel Perfect Web Interface with HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
- Developed some WordPress themes and plugins for clients.
- Developed several hybrid applications using Angular 1.3 and Ionic and published to Google and Apple app store.

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

HUMAN ACTIVITY RECOGNITION USING DEEP LEARNING

TECHNOLOGY: Python, SkLearn, FastAl

MALARIA CELL CLASSIFICATION USING DEEP LEARNING

TECHNOLOGY: Python, FastAl

HUMAN ACTIVITY RECOGNITION USING EXTREME LEARNING

MACHINE

TECHNOLOGY: Python, SkLearn

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

HTML5 Semantic, performant, cross-browser

compatible websites, modern HTML5 APIs

CSS & UX SAAS, SCSS, LESS, Modular CSS paradigms,

Responsive design, Mobile optimization, Bootstrap, Material-UI, TailwindCSS

FRAMEWORKS ReactJS, VueJS, NextJS, NuxtJS, Gridsome,

Gatsby, React Native, Angular 1.3.

STATE MANAGEMENT Zustand, Recoil, VueX

FRONT-END TOOLING NPM, Webpack, Bower, Gulp, Yeoman

BACKEND LANGUAGE Comfortable with PHP + Laravel, Django REST

EXPERIENCE API, FastAPI, Flask.

LANGUAGE SKILL Skilled at conveying complex topics to team

members, writing technical documentation.